You might have seen a semi-viral reel this
week of me giving a barber some
advice. And my barber's seen that video,
and today he said, "I want to make some
content." But he doesn't know
that we're coming to him to make content.
He thinks he's filming me.
We're going to film him because Tesh,
my barber,
he's business-minded. And the point I
was trying to make to him is
that there can
be really cool and interesting
conversations that happen in barber chairs
every day.
Maybe today we can capture some of it.
And the bonus is, the reason Declan
is working for me is
because of Tesh, my barber.
He put me onto Declan.
Declan offered to do work for him for
free. Full circle, all goes around.
So we're going to rock up,
put him on the spot.
We might have to just Simon Squibb the
fuck out of him and say, "Tesh, what
is your
dream?"
And Tesh doesn't know we're coming. Well,
he knows I'm coming.
Just doesn't know you're coming.
Always got to come with gifts,
otherwise you'll make my hairline look
dodgier than
it is.
Tesh.
James, how are you, mate?
Doing the Uno Reverse plus four on you
today.
I'm bringing content to your content.
Fuck.
Have you seen Declan in a while?
It's been a while.
You won't be able to chat shit about him
today.
Nah.
Yeah,
he says he's only got a few years left
till he's going Turkey.
He's hoping there's going to be a miracle
hair loss treatment that comes up
in the next 10 years.
I'd love a little nap. Oh, it's not cold.
Doesn't matter.
Doesn't...
[laughs] You like the new Trank stuff?
Oh,
I need it today as well because I'm tired.
Why, you got boring clients today?
Their hair's a bit mad.
Yeah. Shall we just leave it level?
Yeah.
Do you reckon you could line up the chin a
bit?
Yeah.
But everything else is all right.
Yeah, sweet.
What questions were you going to ask me
today?
Because you were going to try
and content me today.
[laughs] Yeah,
you've reversed it around on me.
But what's interesting
is we always talk about business.
Yeah.
Nothing's off bars,
because I'm usually always yapping on this
channel.
Yeah.
So maybe you take the lead on my channel
today.
Oh, James, come on.
Take the lead on your channel.
How am I going to do that? [laughs]
What do you want to talk about?
What's something you used to believe about
success that turned out to be total
bullshit?
Ooh. Mm.
Something about success.
And I know you're a no-nonsense talker as
well.
You're a straight to the point
and it's what you're known for.
Oh,
this one's going to take a bit of soul
searching, so-
No, that's fine. If you want, we can-
I thought I had success in 2021.
Thought I'd got it.
Because like you said,
you're trying to hit new plateaus all the
time, right?
Yeah. So in 2021, I'm making good money.
I live with my mates.
I'm living the high life.
Then you get a Mrs.
You get a dog. You buy a house.
And then I realized I'm poor.
Mm.
If I die tomorrow, I'm leaving debt.
Yeah.
So then I'm like, "Cool,
I just need a few million dollars-
Mm
... so that if I die-
... the family have a house."
Yeah.
Then you've just got to be in the pursuit
as quick as you can to make those
millions.
Yeah.
So I was happier when I had less.
Now, I always think about people that
are just getting into the housing market
now.
Yeah.
Someone like Declan, he's fucked.
This guy, proper.
He's paying places.
I pay him well, but you know. No,
in a serious note, people know if
they want security.
It's more that generation though,
isn't it?
Yeah,
and if you think about our tax brackets
here-
It's really high. It's like-
Average-
... the highest in the world
... average house price in Sydney is what?
$1.6 million?
About that, yeah.
£800,000.
Down here it's £1 million.
So then that alone means you need 3.2
million, or call it $3 million,
to pay off the house.
Because every $10 you earn,
you've got to give four back to the
government.
Yeah.
So when you've got the most expensive
house prices among the highest tax
brackets
ever-
Yeah
... $3 million.
How long does someone have to earn that?
If they're on 100K a year,
that's 30 years.
So then I thought success
was just being stress-free, blah, blah,
blah.
But now I've realized success for me,
just because I'm moving the goalposts a
lot-
Yeah
... is actually closer to debt-free,
house paid off,
family left with no stress if I die.
Not that I think I'm going to die, but-
Yeah
...
So-
It sounds like what you're saying is,
is that you thought you knew what success
looked like-
Yeah, and then I-
... before your journey.
And then-
And then you hit a point where you
believed that you had it,
and then your whole
life changed. You met your Mrs.
You had little Kian,
your baby.
Mm-hmm.
And then you realized, hold on a minute.
Success is way bigger.
It's a lot bigger than I thought.
It's a lot more late nights.
It's a lot more long days.
It's a lot more being tired.
A lot more sacrifices.
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. So I like that.
So success to me before
was having a chilled life.
Now it's absolutely slogging myself in my
30s.
Yeah. Sacrificing for your family.
Yeah. Mm.
I like that.
But then the thing is, I say this,
but the second I pay that house off,
I'll just
buy a bigger one.
Yeah, okay. Fair enough.
And then I'll just be like, "Oh, fuck."
All right. Let's
stop it there. So
that leads me to my next question.
[laughs]
All right? So you basically said that
if... What did you just say? You said if-
The second I reach that place,
I'll just buy another house.
Yeah, okay.
Because once your mortgage free-
All right. So-
... this house-
And that's you leveling up, right?
So that's great.
So then let's say everything got stripped
from you.
Let's say you lost your brands,
you lost your followers, everything's
gone. All right?
But you're still James Smith.
You still have your brain.
How would you build it all up again
if you had to start all
over?
Interesting question. Do you know
if I lost everything,
there would be a part of me
that was like,
"I'm just going to go work in Bunnings,"
which is the equivalent of
Sainsbury's Homebase.
I don't think you ever could, James.
But they're so happy in there.
I see the old boys in Bunnings.
Yeah.
They're just living the good life.
I think you've seen too much. But yeah,
all right, I hear what you're saying.
But if you had to start all over again-
It would be the exact same because I've
actually done this quite a few times.
So we did fitness,
then I had to start all over again in the
business space because
no one thinks you actually know what
you're on about.
Yeah.
We started a new YouTube channel,
which this video will go on.
Yeah.
We started new Instagram pages.
So it wouldn't bother me having to start
it all over again.
Yeah.
Already I've had to reimagine myself a few
times as from personal trainer to
author, to business to business coach,
to drinks business
founder. So I've already-
So the reason why I ask
is because there are people out there
that are just
starting
So it would sort of just give them some
insight into how you would
approach that, analyze that,
and tackle that.
So that-
Just make so much content
... do you get me?
Mm-hmm.
And that's what you've said to me.
You keep saying it,
and you say it so simply.
You're just like,
"Just get 100 videos out there.
It's the first 100 videos.
Just get 100 videos out there."
All the people that haven't made any
progress in their business,
all I need to do
is just look at their socials,
and then I'm like, "Oh, come here.
It sounds like you're working really hard,
but there's only 124 posts here."
Yeah.
And they're like, "Oh,
but I've got a degree." I'm like,
"I don't give a fuck.
You haven't posted enough for people to
find you and know you,
but you also haven't
posted enough for you to become good
enough."
Yeah.
Imagine if I was like, "Oh, Tash,
I keep losing at jujitsu."
And you go, "How often
are you training?" "Oh,
once a week." Well, the fact of the
matter is,
you're training against people that
are training every day.
You're always going to lose-
Yeah. Well done
... training once a week.
Yeah.
So, like-
So you would just post.
All day every day.
You would just post.
And would you have a strategy behind it,
or your main strategy
would be just-
Lot-
... get videos out there?
There has to be like a main strategy as
far as you've got to know who you're
talking to and what problems you solve.
But anything beyond that isn't a strategy.
So-
It's just procrastination
... so let's say it's like KT again,
right?
Actually, no,
because I've seen a few comments on your
posts as well.
People were asking you know, if you
was a plumber, what would you do?
So let's-
The plumber one was interesting.
Yeah, that was. So let's talk about that.
I've got two brothers,
they're both plumbers.
Okay.
So, and they're both-
Are they self-employed?
Yeah. One of them is.
One of them works at Houses of Parliament.
Okay.
Yeah.
What, in the UK?
Yeah. He's in the Houses of Parliament.
So the one that's self-employed I'd say
gets a better deal because if
he goes on holiday to Geneva,
he could always say he
was at a plumbing convention.
Yeah. [laughs]
Or he could go,
if his mate's a plumber
that lives in Dubai,
they could go to Dubai
and just talk about a plumbing business
they're going to put together.
Yeah.
So the self-employed person's going to
wind up a lot more.
As long as that was exclusively
and wholly for the business.
Whereas your mate at Houses of Parliament,
if he expenses a trip to Dubai, you
can't expense it-
No
... because he's employed, it's PAYE.
Yeah.
So as a plumber,
the most important thing
is you're self-employed, because then if
you're going to do marketing costs-
Yeah
...
or you're going to do a massive flyering
campaign, or you're going to pay the
Royal Mail to go put-
Yeah
...
25,000 plumbing slips in through
everyone's letterboxes, you
need to be able to expense that.
Yeah.
So self-employed would be the start.
Second thing, for a plumber to do well,
he needs more business than he can
handle.
Yeah.
Because then he can start scaling.
So the crux of that would be good
marketing.
I don't think that fridge magnets
are the best way to do it.
Fridge magnets?
You see plumbers that come around,
and like-
So if you was a plumber, though,
how would you transition as a plumber
going online on socials?
So first thing I-
Like what would you do?
What would go through your mind?
So one of the first things would be like
making what content works
already and what can we kind of jump on
the back of?
So if you look at someone like Terry the
Tiler on TikTok, do you know him?
No.
It's a guy called Terry the Tiler who
video records him tiling people's
bathrooms.
Oh, yeah?
It's fucking unreal.
Is he good?
I'm literally... Oh, he's so good.
He's just nice to watch.
Hundreds of thousands of views.
We've got the other guy
that cleans swimming pools
in the UK.
Yeah.
No one actually cares... Well,
like some people care.
Yeah.
But by showing the transformative journey
of before and after, people love the
before and after.
That's why I've always said
that the before and after of the
haircut's really important.
Yeah.
So a plumber arriving at the job,
whether it's a leak,
whether it's changing a tap,
whether it's setting up a shower in the
garden,
there's a transformative journey to
everything the plumber does.
Yeah.
The plumber should showcase that,
and the bonus for me would then be...
The thing is, under my sink-
So it's like-
... is connected to my dishwasher
... the journey.
I haven't got any idea what's going on.
Yeah, same.
But imagine if you did a bit of a video
where you're like, "If you're someone that
wants to swap out your dishwasher,
here are some things you need to know."
Yeah.
And then you're like, "Right,
what type of dishwasher do I need?
What are the hoses around the back?" I
would actually teach people how to do it
themselves so they still wouldn't want to.
Yeah.
For instance,
you could make content teaching people how
to do their own fades.
You could probably get more business out
of that.
Mm.
You know, if
the local car garage
was teaching me how to change my own tire,
I'd probably go
there to get my tires changed.
Yeah.
Just because they're educating you?
So the content wouldn't be my main
strategy as a plumber.
The first thing would be what I call
bricks and mortar marketing.
I'd go flyering around-
What, just to create business, you mean?
Yeah.
Let's say you have the business.
So the flyers, right, I would say is,
the flyers in massive text would say,
"You had a good day today," and under it,
it would say, "Because nothing in your
house is leaking."
And then they turn over and it says,
"One day you're going to
have a burst pipe or a leak in your house-
Yeah
...
and this is the number you need to call."
Yeah.
You know, something like that.
And you could say-
You'll feel safe reading that.
Yeah.
People will go, "Oh yeah."
You go,
"Take a picture of this on your phone."
"That's nice. See,
because I don't know any plumbers.
Boom, stick that on the fridge."
And I'll come round, and you know what?
If I'm busy, I'll send my brother around.
If I'm busy, if he's busy-
We'll send-
...
someone will be at your house within a
couple hours.
Yeah.
And I would say,
"You can call this number 2:00 in the
morning, 3:00 in the
morning."
Yeah.
And then you put those through every
single house.
The next time something happens,
you know that Better Call Saul?
Yeah.
I might even go Better Call Saul branding.
You could be like Better Call Saul
Plumbers.
They'd be like, "My name's not Saul,
but still,
you can call me anything you want.
Keep paying the bill." You can make
content around how much a plumber should
really
charge.
Yeah.
If you've paid over £142 for this,
you've been ripped off by a plumber.
Here's the financial ombudsman input into-
Cutting out business
... yeah, how much it costs.
Getting yourself out there,
getting your name out there.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
So then how many clients do you get from
10,000 flyers?
Might take a lot of time for
that to come into fruition as well,
because some
people might not have a leak for a few
weeks.
Mm-hmm.
But then on that flyer as well,
you could be like, "Even
if there's not a leak, if
you've got some tap or showers
that you want changing in the house-
Yeah
... book in a free quote here."
Yeah. So,
that'd be to build the business.
Mm-hmm.
Then we spoke about potential tax benefits
if you own your
own business-
Mm
... as opposed to working for someone.
And then you also said about online before
and afters would be a
good way to go, or just educating people.
Think about how many haircuts you've done
that never went online.
Think about how many situations-
I was actually thinking about that-
How many situations?
... this week.
How many messy situations have your
barbers cleaned up then never put it on
social media?
Mm.
You know, like even electricians,
they turn up at a job.
I don't know what the three wires do,
the ground, the earth-
Yeah
... the fucking whatever.
All right.
How many posts a week on social media?
As many as you fucking can,
and I'll look at that number,
and I'll know how much
you want it.
Yeah. Okay.
One a day, bare minimum.
That is the truth.
For most people,
because you could always just do a
15-second Reel.
Yeah.
It
doesn't have to be a fucking Oppenheimer
every time.
Just get it out.
Mm-hmm.
Whatever it is, get it out.
Mm-hmm. People are lazy, Tash.
Yeah, I know. I've been learning that.
Yeah.
I've been learning a lot about myself-
Or-
...
especially since I've met you [chuckles]
it's comfortable doing what you're doing
Yeah.
And I'm coming out my comfort zone a lot
now.
I'm
moving very different these days.
I've been learning a lot more.
I'm actually utilizing ChatGPT the way you
told me to.
Content creation, getting more videos out.
Still not a lot, still learning,
but also been writing down
systems for this place,
just to systemize it, so
when we eventually go
into a space-
And what do you need outside?
A car parking space for the Porsche.
Yeah, I've heard about that. [laughs]
What was the other question you had?
So you're known for saying it how it is,
and
that's something I've heard about you
plenty of times.
People are,
"I really like James because he just says
it how it is.
There's no bullshit." So
is there an uncomfortable
truth that men need to hear about trying
to get that
success that they're trying to get?
Do you know what I've started doing, Tash?
I've started-
No bullshit, straight answer
... people in my mentorship-
Yeah
... I've started telling them
if they need to shave their head.
Really?
Yeah. One guy the other day, Scottish lad,
I said, "Sorry, mate, I wouldn't be
doing what you're paying me for
if I didn't say this." I said, "Mate,
you've got to
shave the lid." It
was hanging on by a thread, and I said,
"I should be
listening to what you're saying."
Oh, the uncomfortable truth. [chuckles]
Then another guy, I said to him, "Hey,
mate, I don't know what's going on in your
life,
but you need to..." He's a chiropractor as
well.
Yeah.
I said,
"You need to talk to me about your
composition." I said, "Because if you're
really good at what you do as a chiro,
I will struggle
to respect your opinion as much
if you're fat."
Yeah.
Sounds really harsh.
Bet.
I said, "Mate, call me a cunt,
tell me to fuck off." He has got young
twins, and
so he's got three kids.
Yeah.
So I was like, "Look, cool." But I said,
"You're in a room with 1,100 personal
trainers. If you need help,
you're in the right place." Mate,
and even if it's a
GLP-1 or putting him on some Mounjaro
or something.
That is actually my role as part of his
brand to help him succeed, saying to him,
"Hey, mate, let me help you get in shape."
Oh, yeah.
"Let's lose 15kg." Because although we
don't talk about it enough, even
the reason I get a haircut every week,
how I present myself-
Mm
... is important for trust and-
Yeah, I've learned that about you, though.
I know with you,
you're all for tough love, no bullshit.
If someone's not doing something,
and you can see that they're being lazy or
they're slacking off,
you're straight to the point-
Mate, I've got-
... tough love. You'll never sit there
and be like, "Come on, mate, carry on.
You've got this." You're like, "Mate,
you clearly don't want it.
You're full of shit."
After playing first team at Maidenhead
Rugby Club for a year, every game-
Yeah
... I got dropped.
Yeah.
I went to my coach, and I was like,
"Greeno,
why have you dropped me?" He took a
deep breath, and he went,
"You played like shit at the weekend."
Ah.
He goes,
"You missed loads of fucking tackles."
Yeah.
He goes, "I can't believe
that you played that bad in front of your
mom and dad in
the grandstand."
He said it like that?
Yeah. [chuckles] And went, "Mate, I
was at training first thing
Tuesday. I was, 'Yes, sir. No,
sir.' Making my tackles."
Yeah.
"Not fucking around." The worst thing he
could've ever said to me was, "Oh, Smithy,
mate,
we're just doing a bit of a player
rotation."
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
He made me perform better by telling me
the truth.
He gave you that hard truth.
If he had been kind to me,
it would've been the worst thing he
could've ever done
to me because it would've given me a false
illusion of what the real
situation was.
My mom was like that with me.
If I ever had a fight at school,
if I came back, and
she saw that I had a black eye
or something, she will go,
"You better fucking go
back there and make sure you give them two
black eyes before I give
you another black eye." [laughs] I swear,
she's tough love.
You see, someone got annoyed on
that comment.
When I did that video for the boxing
coach, and I was like,
"Rip a liver shot to
your husband"-
Yeah
... someone was like, "Oh,
you think domestic violence is funny,
do you?" It's
like, oh, for fuck's sake.
Some people take things too literally,
Harry.
I was about to nibble, and I thought,
"It's not worth it."
[chuckles]
It's not worth it. [plastic rattling]
Oh, god.
Oh, I feel 10 years younger.
Still going bald, though. Oh, hardly.
I think your hair's just real blonde.
Yeah, that's what they all say.
That's what it is. It's just-
Real blonde.
I was asking ChatGPT about minoxidil.
Yeah.
Can it make your scalp dry?
I don't know. All I know is
that the minoxidil I've heard of
is 5% extra strength.
Mm.
And I think it comes with a little syringe
in there, and you're supposed to apply
it to your scalp. But what I have heard,
it's more beneficial
if you-
Take pills
... have a derma roller-
Oh, yeah
... and then apply it. Or
if you've had a fresh hair transplant,
you're supposed to put 5% extra strength
in there, and also to get
that... Is that PRP?
Hmm. Platelet-rich plasma.
Yeah, apparently that, and then
that would help all your new ones-
Seems like a lot of admin
... there. There's a lot.
You have to take finasteride as well.
You can't just take minoxidil. No.
Not taking finasteride.
I just don't like the finasteride.
Yeah. The side effects for finasteride,
what you're saying is right, though, 100%.
Mm.
But the side effects for finasteride
are quite detrimental to men's health.
Yeah. I just don't want the boner killers.
Yeah. There's that, and apparently-
Oh,
you want to know what's a good boner
killer?
Go on.
Jet lag.
Jet lag? I don't know.
I haven't been jet lagged for a little
while.
God bless. Mate, it's horrible.
Oh, I think I'm in good nick. [chuckles]
I'm not going anywhere ever again after
that trip.
[chuckles] Oh,
you'll be gone in the next month or two.
You can't sit still. Big time.
All right. We're coming to the end.
Last question. You got one?
Last question.
Probably, do you like your haircut?
Yeah. How's the haircut?
Perfect. Nice and simple now.
Is that all right for you?
Yeah. Good. Do you know what?
I've been flirting with the idea of
bringing it back.
What, at the top?
Yeah, just bringing a bit of length back.
Why not? Bit of shit and giggles.
But not today. Couldn't be-
Look, I personally think with your hair,
I think a little bit more length, but
short on the sides would go really nice.
Mm.
And then obviously the stubble as well.
Yeah.
That's just a personal opinion,
but it's completely up to you what you
want to do.
And if someone in Wollongong wants to book
in, we'll put a link in the description.
I tell you what,
if you've got a local business in Sydney,
and you want to grow it,
send location. Declan and I will show up,
and we'll help you.
We'll get boots on the ground.
Give you a free hour of consultancy,
as long as we
can film it. And you've got a whiteboard.
Love a whiteboard.